Amy Bridges

I have worked remotely since 2006 mostly as a freelancer and contractor. I have been noticed as a top WordPress developer worldwide. I like to contribute to WordPress core and contribute coding time to open source projects such as Rocket Chat.

South Park, PA

<u>ubergeekzone@gmail.com</u>

<u>linkedin.com/in/ubergeekzone</u>

github.com/ubergeekzone

EXPERIENCE

Freelancing, Pittsburgh PA— Web Engineer

JANUARY 2020 - PRESENT

Creating WordPress websites for small business owners that increase brand awareness. Helping agencies scale by strategic partnerships that offer robust web development solutions. Working with tech stacks such as WooCommerce, Laravel, Shopify, and Vue. Managing daily operations such as scheduling meetings, marketing, and sales.

Human Made, New York (Remote) — Web Engineer

OCTOBER 2021 - MAY 2022

Working technology stacks such as WordPress, AWS, Docker and Vagrant. Team communication collaboration on daily tasks such as WordPress theme creation or plugin creation. Helping solve client problems by providing insights of resolutions on tasks at hand. Using slack and zoom as team communication tools. Working with project managers to plan project tickets by reviewing a summary of work and time tasks will take to complete.

Moving Company Reviews, Part Time — Full Stack Developer

NOVEMBER 2020 - JANUARY 2021

Working with WordPress powered websites. Creating custom plugins and themes. Increased CR by 20% for mobile by adding past customer reviews functionality to the website. Managing Google Tags and Analytics for Callrail Integration.

WakaTime, Part Time — Full Stack Developer

JANUARY 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2021

Creating and maintaining plugins for code editors using Java that allow time tracking with ide's and helping integrate new 3rd party software into the website.

ROLE

Full Stack Web Engineer

SKILLS

WordPress

React

GIT

LAMP

REST

Composer & NPM

AWS

Docker

Vue

HTML5 & CSS3

PHP

LANGUAGES

English

CODE CONTRIBUTIONS

Rocket.Chat on Github

Codeable, Denmark (Remote) — WordPress Developer

DECEMBER 2017 - JANUARY 2020

Full Stack WordPress Developer responsible for creating WordPress plugins and themes and providing custom development services. Creating Scope Of Work Documents to help customers make informed decisions about project cost, timeline, and requirements. Increased customer satisfaction by 20% and customer retention by 35%.

Maje Media, Minnesota (Remote) — Front End Developer

MAY 2018 - OCTOBER 2018

Front End Developer responsible for creating custom WordPress themes from PSD designs and helping with routine maintenance on websites.

Tayse Rugs, Calhoun GA — Full Stack Web Developer

SEPTEMBER 2017 - NOVEMBER 2017

Full Stack Web Developer responsible for creating eCommerce software to assist the eCommerce department with the management of wholesale to retail product imports. Created Web Applications that mapped data from the master product spreadsheet into retailer formatted spreadsheet for import. Increased productivity time by 45% in the eCommerce department by freeing up manual interaction for product import management.

Trip Craft, Massachusetts (Remote) — Front End Developer

JUNE 2015 - FEBRUARY 2016

Front End Developer responsible for creating web and mobile applications for the hospitality industry. Increased booking of rooms by 20% for hotels through mobile user interaction flow. Agile Development process using Jira working on a team of 10 other developers with project managers.

EDUCATION

Sequoyah High School, Canton GA — *High School*

PROJECTS

Socket.IO Chat Starter — *Custom Chatroom System Starter Kit* https://github.com/ubergeekzone/socketio-chat-starter

On Human —Agency Management System For Humans https://github.com/ubergeekzone/onhuman

Bitbucket Issues for Atom Editor - C# Operating System Dev https://github.com/ubergeekzone/bitbucket-issues